BEATRICE SCHEMBRI

JUNIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER

Living in different countries has given me the chance to gain experience in a variety of jobs and to keep challenging myself. Being organized, flexible, quick to learn and open to communication are the skills I mostly rely upon.

I joined an intensive bootcamp to reskill as junior developer. I have been focusing on **backend tools and frameworks**, with the goal of specializing in software development. My mission is to contribute to a more accessible, sustainable, and fairer world by building efficient solutions, bit by bit.

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript,

Node.js, Express, PHP, Laravel,

SQL databases

Tools: Git / Github, VSCode

Learning: Cloud computing, C#

LANGUAGES

Italian native

English full working proficiency

Spanish limited working proficiency

Dutch basic understanding

EDUCATION

JUNIOR DEVELOPER COURSE

BeCode, Ghent (BE) 2022-2023

Hands-on training, solo & group projects

Q Lier, Belgium

■ beatrice.schembri@gmail.com

+ 32 (0)493 181847

github.com/BiceSchembri

in beatrice-schembri-3a0a1077/

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE TRANSLATOR

Introhive, Canada

01/2020 - 06/2020

English-to-Italian translation of a SaaS app - UI and manuals. Optimized localization for the Italian market.

SALES ASSISTANT

Coles - Indigo, Saint John (Canada)

08/2019 - 11/2019

Bookshop assistant. Inventory and shelving, customer service, loyalty program promotion.

LIBRARY ASSISTANT

Disley Library, Disley (UK)

08/2018 - 05/2019

Public library and community centre assistant. Loans, shelving, activities planning. Assisting patrons with council forms.

BOOKSHOP VOLUNTEER

Oxfam Bookshop, Chorlton (UK)

11/2017 - 05/2019

Second-hand charity shop assistant. Sorting and pricing donated books, floor displays, customer service, opening and closing with cash up.

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

ILPACK Startup, Portugalete (Spain)

06/2016 - 10/2017

Customer service and CRM for a furniture e-commerce. Website and catalogue translation, copywriting (products, blog and SEO).

ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

N.IN.E., Pisa (Italy)

04/2013 - 05/2015

Office assistant in a nuclear engineering firm. Reception desk during conference. Member of the IYCE'15 event Local Organizing Committee.